hi coach bre and here this video is
going to go over three different methods
that I use in my training that are
submaximal uh methods meaning you don't
use maximum weights and these three
methods include the dynamic effort
method the pause
method and the super strict method so
I'll explain this if every time you go
into the gym you crush Yourself by
either using maximum weight or repping
out to failure that's a rep recipe for
disaster if you train frequently like I
do you know I like to train four days a
week so I can't Crush myself you know
twice a week on deadlifts and squats and
bench press uh it would be too much so
one day a week I will go
heavy but the other day uh during the
week I will use one of these methods so
I'll go over all three of them my
favorite method uh I like the the the
super strict method the most and then I
also like the pause method and I like
Dynamic effort as well just not quite as
much as the other but all three of these
are very effective many many lifters
swear by the dynamic effort method uh I
don't like it quite as much but it's you
can't deny its Effectiveness when there
are world you know world class power
lifters who swear by it so let me go
over all three of them for you first is
I'll go over the super strict method the
super strict method so my one rep max
Deft is 600 lb and this is as you can
see 315 on the bar so this is U I'm not
sure say around 55% of my one rep max or
something like that what I'm going to do
is set up and I'm going to use a strict
Arch now I'm not going to pull as fast
as possible but I'm going to use such
good form that I might I make it feel
hard you know and I'm going
to make sure to be very arched I'm going
to drag it up my legs I'm going to
finish off with my glutes I'm going to
control the Ecentric so this way you can
get a good training effect and your
working technique here but you're not
going super
heavy so looks like this
all
right I found this way of training very
very
effective I love going this way it
doesn't Crush you it doesn't beat you up
it improves your form and it increases
your strength because you do that one
you do that one day a week and then
maximum strength one day a week and it's
like a you know a one two punch for
strength
Gates now the next method I'm going to
go over is the pause
method now for bench
presses you will pause at the chest you
can also pause and come up and pause
like an inch off of the chest but I like
pausing right at the
chest the pause is going to be around
say 3 seconds with squats I don't like
with squats I don't like to pause in the
very bottom from here I like to come
down and come up to about parallel and
pause because the sticking region in a
squat is around
there now you could say the sticking
region in in a bench press is off the
chest as well in which case you'd be
right but I've just found
that on the chest works best for bench
for squats a parallel
position and then for deadlifts just
like an inch or two off the ground works
best so here's what pause reps looks
like for deadness I'm going to line
up I'm going to come about an inch off
the
ground one 2 3
all right so that's the pause
method notice I did around a 3se second
pause right off the
floor and that's the best place to pause
for the de in my
opinion all right now the last method
I'm going to go over it's a dynamic
effort
method I do feel like you need some
experience to get good at the dynamic
effort
method if you're a
beginner in my opinion you should be
doing maximum you know maximum loading
maximum
effort uh repetitive effort method going
you know close to failure while keeping
good
form and then Super strict method and
pause method you maybe shouldn't do the
dynamic effort because your form isn't
good enough but once you've been
training you know one to two years with
good form and you've gotten strong then
the dynamic effort method can be very
effective and all you're trying to do
here is just be as explosive as possible
while still using good form and control
so um you can do one rep two reps three
reps four reps five reps I wouldn't go
above five
reps some power lifters like to do
singles with their Dynamic effort again
there's a lot of ways to do things but
with all three of these submaximal
effort uh methods you're using lighter
weights so it doesn't crush your central
nervous system so again right now I'm
using you know 55% of my One MA and I'm
getting a good training effect out of it
so this year is 315 I'm going to do a
set of
three I am not going to bounce it off
the floor I'm going to reset every
repetition so it looks like
this so as you can see that way was way
faster than the other
two one way to increase the
effectiveness of dynamic effort is to
utilize bands or chains chains can can
be tricky when you're deadlifting
because they can get in the way of the
plates and bands work best with a
platform you can stand on bands but I
don't like that method too much anyway
notice with the dynamic effort I
accelerate as the bar comes up
and I don't take any slack out of my
elbows but I do accelerate the bar and
push with my hips but I'm I'm squeezing
my glutes to lock out so you'll see the
bar kind of move forward just a little
bit and that's because my arms are
locked out my glutes squeeze forward and
push the hips forward and it kind of
goes like this and that's just because
this weight is so light for me it's not
a problem to explode
upwards anyway I really feel like these
three methods helped bring my strength
to the next
level um done on their own they're not
going to be as effective as when
combined when you're using maximum
strength in tandem but
again you know I'm 37 years old I don't
try to crush myself every single time I
go into the gym um and I sometimes I'll
use like I'll do
you know a heavy squat or front squat
and I might follow it up with Dynamic
effort or sub maximal you know pause
reps or super strict reps of another
lift and this way I can train more
frequent I can train the lifts more
frequently anyway I hope you enjoy the
video I hope this sheds some light on
how you can use sub maximum weights
without going as heavy as possible
without repping out to failure you know
if I wanted to I could probably do 3 15
for 30 reps but that's not going to
build strength as well as doing a heavy
session once per week and then doing
these once per week uh in my opinion
thanks for watching